<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Reasons, for enlarging and regulating the trade to Russia and the Narve.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A92225</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R493</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225006</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">45097907</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 45097907</idno>
            <idno type="VID">171484</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A92225)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 171484)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2575:30)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Reasons, for enlarging and regulating the trade to Russia and the Narve.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Encourages the admission of other merchants into the Russia Company.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Sutro Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Muscovy Company.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Commerce --  Russia --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Russia --  Commerce --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:171484:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 39 -->
            <head>REASONS, For Enlarging and Regulating The Trade to RUSSIA and the NARVE.</head>
            <p>1655. <hi>6 Febr. Annis 1<hi rend="sup">o</hi> &amp; 2<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Philip. &amp; Mar.</hi> The ſaid King and Queen by their Charter to the <hi>RUSSIA</hi>—COMPANY, Granted them the Sole TRADE to all the Main-Lands, Iſles, Ports, &amp;c. of the Emperour of <hi>Ruſſia;</hi> at which time the <hi>Narve,</hi> (a Port in the <hi>Baltick</hi> Sea) belonged to the ſaid Emperour.</p>
            <p>1581. The ſaid Port was taken from the Emperour by the <hi>Swede,</hi> who has Poſſeſſed it ever ſince.</p>
            <p n="1">I. THE <hi>Ruſſia</hi>-Company having enjoyed the ſaid Trade ever ſince 1555, which is now above 140 Years <hi>excluſivè,</hi> to others; it may be ſuppoſed (with ſubmiſſion) that they have received a very ample Recompence for the Expences, Pains, and Hazard of their firſt Diſcovery. And therefore the Admiſſion into the <hi>Ruſſia</hi>-Company, may be made more eaſy to all <hi>Engliſh</hi> Merchants in general.</p>
            <p n="2">II. And it would be for the Nations Intereſt, to permit any <hi>Engliſh</hi> Merchant to take his Freedom of the ſaid Company, upon eaſy Terms. For the Merchants of the <hi>Ruſſia</hi>-Company, and all other Merchants of <hi>England,</hi> are daily admitted into the ſeveral Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms of the <hi>Hamburgh</hi> and <hi>Eaſtland</hi> Companies, for a Fine of 40 <hi>s.</hi> (the Fine of Admiſſion into the <hi>Eaſtland</hi>-Company having been reduced by Parliament to that Sum) on purpoſe to make the Admiſſions into that Company eaſy to all <hi>Engliſh</hi> Merchants: and the Fine of the <hi>Hamburgh</hi>-Company hath ſince been reduced by themſelves to the like Sum, and for the like Reaſon.</p>
            <p n="3">III. That at preſent the ſaid Company burden the Trade from <hi>Narve</hi> with a great Impoſition, where they themſelves Trade little or nothing; and lay no Duty at all on the Trade from <hi>Archangel,</hi> which they wholly reſerve for themſelves. Whereas, in reaſon the Impoſitions on all the Trade, both from <hi>Archangel</hi> and <hi>Narve,</hi> ought to be laid equally.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. Heretofore the ſaid Company did permit Perſons to Buy their Freedom for 60 <hi>l.</hi> But ſeveral Years ſince they made a By-Law, to Admit none into their Company, on any Terms whatever, unleſs by Service. Whereas the Admiſſions into other Companies, may be had for 40 <hi>s.</hi> as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p n="5">V. That Maſts, Timber and Firr-plank, Hemp, Pitch and Tar may be imported from <hi>Ruſſia,</hi> at cheaper Rates than they can be had from <hi>Pruſſia, Denmark, Sweden</hi> or <hi>Norway.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="6">VI. In Caſe of a War with the Countreys laſt named, (which uſually in time of Peace furniſh us with thoſe Naval Commodities) we may be ſupplied with the like or better ſorts, from <hi>Ruſſia.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:171484:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 40 -->
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:171484:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 41 -->
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 span">
               <desc>〈1 span duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <p n="7">VII. That the <hi>Ruſſes</hi> having no Ships of their own, all ſuch Maſts, Timber and Plank, and all other Commodities brought thence for <hi>England,</hi> will be Imported in <hi>Engliſh</hi> Ships; and ſo the Freight of them (which oft times is double or treble to the firſt Coſts of the Goods) will be gained to this Nation. Whereas the Maſts, Timber and Plank, Hemp, Pitch and Tar which are Imported from <hi>Pruſſia, Denmark, Sweden</hi> and <hi>Norway,</hi> are gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally Imported in Foreign Ships; whereby the whole Freight is totally loſt to us, and gained by Foreigners.</p>
            <p n="8">VIII. As a farther Conſequence of the <hi>Ruſſes</hi> having no Shipping, they will thereby be rendred uncapable of Entring into a Sea-War; and ſo We ſhall have the greater likely<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood of always enjoying a free and open Trade with them, for thoſe ſorts of Commodities, which in time of War with <hi>Pruſſia, Denmark</hi> or <hi>Sweden,</hi> cannot be had from any Foreign Countrey.</p>
            <p n="9">IX. By the great Impoſitions paid to the <hi>Ruſſia</hi>-Company, all our Naval Stores Imported from <hi>Narve</hi> are made dearer to us; and particularly that of Flax, of which We make our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Sail-Cloth; which ought rather to have all poſſible Eaſe and Encouragement, than to be Burthened with unneceſſary Duties to a Private Company.</p>
            <p n="10">X. The making the Admiſſions of other Merchants eaſy into the Company, will Enlarge the Trade to <hi>Ruſſia;</hi> which being a cold Country, and of large Extent, will Encourage a greater Exportation of the Woollen and other Commodities of the Growth and Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>facture of this Kingdom, and of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Plantations, than the <hi>Ruſſia</hi>-Company do Export.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
